<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on lucasew's offtopic</title><link>/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on lucasew's offtopic</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hashbang hacking for fun and, maybe in the future, profit</title><link>/post/20240717-hashbang-hacking-for-fun-and-maybe-in-the-future-profit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/20240717-hashbang-hacking-for-fun-and-maybe-in-the-future-profit/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the story of how I created a thing to make self contained scripts. It&amp;rsquo;s basically a Nix flakes based workaround, so the environment of a script can be automatically provisioned before the actual script starts without having to install stuff globally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am a Nix user, and as a Nix user, I tend to put Nix in everything. At least everything that I think it makes sense.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hashbangs are the UNIX-like way to make a text file executable, so it becomes a program, and a pain point I have is that there is so much boilerplate to have something simple to start hacking on something. In a non-Nix distro one would have to install many packages and pray for them to not conflict with each other, build some kind of boilerplate like a package.json for a Node application, or a requirements.txt for a Python application, or a pom.xml, or Gradle, for a Java project. What if I do it a little different?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How I entered the state of flow reviewing PRs in nixpkgs</title><link>/post/20241224-nixpkgs-reviewd-flow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/20241224-nixpkgs-reviewd-flow/</guid><description>&lt;p>For those that don&amp;rsquo;t know, I am a Linux user, specifically a NixOS user
(and I expect memes incoming about this) for over 4 years,
&lt;a href="https://github.com/lucasew/nixcfg/commit/10ed3d3c9ed02b97bb0d82545499a9fc51a39e63" target="_blank"
 rel="external" >2020-07-37 to be exact&lt;/a>,
and eventually in the Nix world you will need to engage in nixpkgs somehow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have over 100 PRs there, some of them adding modules,
some of them adding packages, some maintaining packages
and some failed experiments (&lt;a href="https://github.com/lucasew/nixcfg/blob/b754398dd6e699c5bedbf0317e9661894a5f85ec/nix/nodes/bootstrap/port-alloc.nix" target="_blank"
 rel="external" >that some of them I don&amp;rsquo;t consider exactly failed&lt;/a>).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>